# MAICOL CAMARGO

230 Chalmers Street Sydney, Redefern 2016, NSW

Mobile: (+61) 415 376 941 mfcamargoh@gmail.com

### SUMMARY

Dedicated and hardworking Geographic Information Systems professional with over four years of experience applying geographic analysis and technologies for improved information management and decision support. Expertise includes satellite image processing, land cover mapping and related accuracy assessment; land use optimization and allocation model design; participatory environmental risk assessment; spatial decision support for planning of efficient land use and adaptation of rural lands. Approachable and able to get along with both work colleagues and senior managers, currently looking to work for an organisation offering continued growth and development opportunities.

## SKILL HIGHLIGHTS

- ArcGIS, Quantum GIS, MapInfo and AutoCAD software
- Digitization and Geoprocessing including overlay analysis
- Editing & creation of data using ArcEditor and COGO
- Map production
- Raster Creation
- Creation of databases

- Model Builder
- Address match & geocoding techniques
- Vector property maps
- Documentations & reporting
- · Basic Python scripting
- Creation of tables & reports using Microsoft products

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **GIS ANALYST ENGINEER**

OCTOBER 2013 - DECEMBER 2015

Unidad de Planificación Rural Agropecuaria - UPRA. Colombia

- Activities of spatial analysis and systematization of geoprocessing models
- Integrated algorithms and methodologies that contribute to answer the requirements for the planning of efficient land use and adaptation of rural lands
- Modeling algorithms for process optimization analysis of geographic information of interes
- Complete special requests utilizing existing data analyzing results and producing reports maps and supporting documentation
- Coordinate with other professionals and analysts in various data development and project support initiatives

#### **GIS ANALYST**

JANUARY 2014 - DECEMBER 2015

Departamento Administrativo Nacional de Estadística - DANE. Colombia

- Integration of geographic and alphanumeric information of cartographic databases as input using aerial photographs and satellite images available
- Creation of cartographic products that will support the realization of the XVIII National Population Census
- Produced statistical graphs and reports for the dissemination of results of phase I of the 3rd
  National Agricultural Census
- Developed and created GIS maps as requested using ArcGIS software and analyzing relevant data
- Collecting and interpreting geographical data for urban planning use

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **GIS STRUCTURER**

June 2013 - December 2014

AUGUST 2012 - DECEMBER 2012

OCTOBER 2011 - DECEMBER 2011

Instituto Geografico Agustin Codazzi – IGAC. Colombia

- Digitized thematic cartography of soils for different projects developed in the sub-direction of Agrology
- Captured, edited and updated cartographic bases at scale 1: 25000 using satellite orthoimagery, optical and radar, ortophotomosaics and airborne radar mosaics.
- Performed and conducted final quality checks of GIS versioned data before it is posted to the GIS
- Edited map features and its correlating attribute data in the GIS
- Developed spatial data overlays and comparisons tests topology for structure and accuracy of spatial data components of centerline files and parcel polygons and datasets assuring sound principles and no gaps overlaps or duplicates.

#### GIS TECHNICIAN

SEPTEMBER 2012 - DECEMBER 2012

Valoración Económica Ambiental – VEA. Colombia

- Support the collection, analysis and systematization of georeferenced information to integrated management of water resources and renewable natural resources in macro basins Magdalena, Cauca and Caribbean in Colombia.
- Created, maintained, and updated GIS data and supported in easy statistical analysis
- Conducting spatial analyses and creating information products
- Assisted in the preparation of technical presentations and proposals when required

#### **GIS TECHNICIAN**

SEPTEMBER 2012 - DECEMBER 2012

Ecointegral Ltda. Colombia

- Updated inventory of georeference investment projects of Water and Sewer data networks
- Used GIS technology and developed maps, data, and reports
- Updated spatial data and support in research and acquisition of spatial data
- Produced cartographic products for public and private agencies

# **EDUCATION**

# **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS**

- Diploma of Website
  Development: Strathfield
  College. Sydney NSW,
  Australia 2017 -2018
- Specialist in Geographic Information Systems - GIS: Universidad Distrital

Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas. Bogotá D.C, Colombia 2013 -2014

 Bachelor of Cadastral and Geodetic Enginner:

Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas. Bogotá D.C, Colombia 2006-2012

#### **COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS**

- Gis on the Web: Lynda.com. 2018
- Real World Gis: Lynda.com. 2018
- Smart Cities: Solving Urban Problems Using Technology: Lynda.com. 2017
- Programming Foundations: Fundamentals:Lynda.com. 2017
- Use of GIS Technology
  GIS in Urban Planning: Organization of American States -OEA. 2011
- ArcGIS Desktop II: Tools and Functionalities.
  Esri Colombia. 2010
- ArcGIS Desktop III: Workflow and Analysis GIS. Esri Colombia. 2010
- Performing Analysis with ArcGIS Desktop. Esri Colombia. 2010
- Introduction to Geoprocessing Scripts Using Python. Esri Colombia. 2010
- AutoCAD Basic Course: SENA, Colombia, 2009

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

# INTERNSHIP

 GIS Intern: GDR Group 65 Pirrama Road, Pyrmont. NSW. 2017

## **PUBLICATIONS**

• Zoning commercial forest plantations in Colombia. Scale 1:100.000.

# LANGUAGES

- Spanish: Mother Tongue Navite Level
- English: Reading, Writing and Verbal skills. Level B2

## **REFERENCES**

# Luz Mery Gómez

GIS Head Officer UPRA. Bogotá, Colombia Mobile: (+57) 3002062744 e-mail: luzmery.gomez@upra.gov.co

# **Shuyun Dong**

GIS Officer GDR Group. Sydney, Australia. Mobile: (+61) 423875497 e-mail: shuyund@gdrgroup.com.au